Shugaba Abraham Wuta

shugabawuta@gmail.com github.com/Shugaba-Wuta • linkedin.com/in/Shugaba-Wuta

Software Engineer

Summary Statement

A Graduate of Software Engineering (BSc.) with 2 years of solid experience in creating RESTful API and web development. Actively participated in the development of a top-down recursive descent compiler called HaPy.
Creator of YouTube Migrate, a tool to migrate YouTube subscriptions and playlists. Developed e-commerce RESTful API using ExpressJS (currently in test). Currently building a full stack intern portal for National Information
Technology Development Agency. Proficient with NodeJS, Python, ExpressJS, FastAPI, TypeScript, ReactJS, Docker, Celery, Redis, RabbitMQ and AWS, but still willing to learn more technology as work demands. Professionally, Shugaba is Interested in but not limited to remote full-stack developer roles and can take on deployment responsibility for AWS. Other interests include jogging, economics, artificial general intelligence, embedded systems and photography. Shugaba believes that consistent hard work reaps success, but when coupled with integrity, honesty and responsibility, it yields long-term success and respect.

Work Experience

Oayastech Nigeria Limited October 2022 – March 2023

(Principal Backend and Deployment Engineer)

- Used ExpressJS, MongooseJS, NodeJS, Paystack to develop robust API backend for e-commerce apps. Also tested API using Postman.
- Extensively used of AWS: Used AWS S3 Bucket to store files uploaded to the API, Elastic Bean Stalk to host backend,
 Simple Emailing Service and Code Pipeline for automated CI/CD from GitHub. Also used Namecheap to manage subdomains.
- Led and collaborated with the front-end developer to deliver the final product that satisfies requirement.

National Information Technology Development Agency May 2022 - Present

(Software Engineer)

- Restored website files from Wayback machine.
- The organization had trouble keeping the records for interns. Stepped in and developed a full-stack portal using TypeScript, React and ExpressJS. Solution was well accepted by the Human Resource department. Received recommendation from the Director-General of the organization for the effective solution created.

Projects

YouTube Migrate

- Developed a server-side rendered web application using Python's FastAPI, Jinja2 templating engine, Bootstrap and Vanilla JS that migrates multiple YouTube subscriptions and playlists.
- Used Celery, RabbitMQ and Redis to run and save persist data from the time-consuming Playlist migrate in the background.
- Used Docker, Nginx Proxy Manager, and AWS EC2 instance to host web application.

HaPy (Hausa Python): A Beginner Programming Language based on Hausa Language

- Implemented and debugged a top-down recursive descent interpreter using Python, created RESTful API and online code editor using Python, FastAPI and SQL Alchemy ORM.
- Collaborated with the team leader to refactor code base and system architecture.

Education

Bachelor of Science (BSc) in Software Engineering (cum laude)

American University of Nigeria, September 2017 – December 2021

Honors and Awards: Member AUN Honor Society, Recipient of Sigma Pensions Award for Academic Excellence.

Volunteering

- Tutored Freshers and Sophomores in university algebra, pre-calculus and calculus, January 2018 May 2021.
- Honor Society: Tutored computer science and software engineering courses, September 2019 May 2021.
- New student orientation volunteer, September 201 8– January 2020.
- Member technical department Church of the Brethren Nigeria (CBN) Utako, August 2022 Present.
- Group President NYSC- Environmental Protections and Sanitation Wednesday, November 2022 March 2023.